MADISON POWELL

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

(615) 601-2445 | madsnpowell@gmail.com | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

ABOUT

I am a full-stack software developer with an interest in UI/UX design. I have a background in psychology research and work experience in customer service. I am creative, organized, and passionate about developing code that works for all users.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

The Light Side of the Force

The Light Side of the Force is a **REACT** application which offers self-help content, presented through the lens of Star War Jedi. It's built with a local **JSON API** and styled entirely with **CSS**. *View Code*

Nutshell

Nutshell is a **REACT** social media application with articles, friends, messages, tasks, and events. I was responsible for implementing both friends and messages. The friend list only shows friends for the logged in user. A new message automatically posts a timestamp and the author's name, then sorts the messages by timestamp.

<u>View Code</u>

Sprinkles of Joy

Sprinkles of Joy is a **javascript** app that was already built out with broken code and many errors. My teammate and I worked together to debug the code, then worked on implementing new features to meet MVP, and refactor the code layout to make the application user-friendly.

<u>View Code</u>

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Software Development Bootcamp - Certificate

Middle Tennessee State University

B.S in Psychology Dean's List, Summa Cum Laude

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML
- React
- Python

- CSS
- JSON Server
- Django

- Javascript
- Bootstrap
- SQL

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full-Stack Software Developer

NSS is a six-month intensive, full-time software development bootcamp focusing on HTML, CSS, Javascript, and React and server-side fundamentals with Python and Django.

- Single-page application development with React and with a focus on modern ES6+ Javascript features and modular code
- Project management with issue tickets and GitHub Projects
- Database planning by building entity relationship diagrams (ERD) to define relationships with an emphasis on maintaining a flat data structure
- Utilized vanilla JavaScript (ES6), and React.js to create a single page dynamic wed application using full CRUD functionality
- Manually styled applications using primarily CSS
- Completed 6 group project sprints while fully remote, comfortable with Slack, Zoom, GitHub Projects, and wireframes for group communication and collaboration

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

STARBUCKS

Barista, Barista Trainer 2014 – 2016, July - November 2020

- Facilitated initial one-on-one trainings for newly hired partners, teaching Starbucks' company values, essential bar skills, and required coffee knowledge
- Maintained a calm demeanor in periods of high volume or shift changes to keep the store running
- Prepared and served quality handcrafted beverages

BEST BRANDS INC.

Front Desk Administrator March 2019 – January 2020

Best Brands Inc. is one of the top alcohol distributors in Nashville, TN.

- Greeted all incoming clients and answered phones with excellent customer service and a friendly disposition
- Processed all incoming orders on regular half hour intervals, while multitasking and completing all other work
- Checked inventory and ordered all office supplies. Kept the front office and supply closet neat and organized

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

L.A. JACKSON

Bar Server May 2018 - August 2018

- Delivered quality guest service within company's standards
- Worked for 78 hours every week with mental strength and determination
- Worked well under pressure and in a constantly challenging environment
- Regularly took on extra shifts and covering for colleagues
- Gained a comprehensive knowledge of inventory on hand, drink mechanics and drink pricing

KILLEBREW

After Dark Barista, June 2018 - July 2018

- Solely operated and closed the coffee shop, taking all orders and preparing all drinks in a seven-hour shift without back-up
- Served coffee, espresso, beer, and wine to Thompson Hotel guests and Killebrew customers after hours
- Prepared high quality beverages from a full espresso menu, dialing in the espresso, tamping and pouring clear latte art

FIDO CAFE

Front of House August 2017 - January 2018

- Took orders, delivered food and drinks, and interacted with customers to ensure a quality dining experience
- Performed daily restaurant operations such as answering phones, prepping food and drinks, stocking, and cleaning tasks
- Worked competently and thrived in fast paced, high stress work environment
- Memorized café's food menu and the ingredient list of each item to assist customers in ordering and to accommodate any allergies or food preferences

JUST LOVE COFFEE ROASTERS

Barista/Production Associate September 2016 - July 2017

- Distinguished the roast, notes, aroma, and acidity of all 26 whole bean single-origin and coffee blends offered
- Prepared high quality espresso drinks, manually measuring and dialing the espresso, tamping, and pouring latte art
- Closed the cafe and performed all closing tasks including balancing the tills, deep cleaning, and locking up
- Fulfilled whole sale coffee bean orders to all online customers and business partners of Just Love

AWARDS

- Partner of the Quarter Starbucks
- Starbucks M.U.G. Award (Moves of Uncommon Greatness)
- Barista Championship Second Runner Up
- Starbucks Training Certificate